僵尸国度前景提要
Previously on Z Nation.
都是僵尸咬的
Those are zombie bites.
有八个
Eight of them.
如果我们可以把他带到加利福尼亚的实验室
If we can get him to the lab in California,
他们就可以研究他的血做更多的疫苗了
they can use his blood and make more of the vaccine.
-射死他 -
- Shoot him! -
你就是那个救了我小命的神枪手吗
You're that sharp shooter that saved my ass, aren't you?
你叫什么 小子
So what's your name, kid?
一万
Ten Thousand.
什么意思
Does it mean anything?
我要杀死的僵尸数
How many zombies I'm going to kill.
One thousand fifty-nine.
One thousand sixty!
干得好 小子
Nice shot, kid!
视频字幕由 SSK字幕组 制作发布
字幕只供学习 请勿做任何商业行为
敬请关注新浪微博@SSK字幕组
翻译：考拉 金刚妹 Windy 冬可可
僵尸
国度
第一季  第四集
宾夕法尼亚州
阿米什乡村
校对：金刚妹 Jophy
阿曼门诺派的僵尸
Amish zombies.
搞什么
Really?
逗我吗
总监：Jophy 时间轴：络睿 压制：呵呵姐
他们以自我隔离
They tried to quarantine themselves
来和其他的团体分开
from the rest of society.
防止僵尸病毒的传染
Keep the Zs from spreading the infection.
那也是罗梅罗沦陷以前的事儿了
That was before we knew Romero had it right.
我们都携带着病毒
We were all carrying the virus.
你是谁 怎么死的都不重要了
Didn't matter who you were or how you died.
活死人之夜 看电影还不错 真变这样也太衰了
Night of the Living Dead. Great movie, sucky reality.
我一直没搞懂 如果不是僵尸传播了病毒
You know what I don't get, If the Zs didn't spread the virus,
为什么我们全部感染了
how did we all get infected?
我听过的最靠谱的说是通过鸟来传播
Best guess I heard, it was spread by birds.
以鸟类病毒的寄生虫为载体
Some kind of parasite piggybacked on the bird flu.
只要你活着 就一直潜藏在你体内
Stays dormant 'till you die.
要我
You know
这个有亲身体验的人来说的话
take it from somebody who knows first hand.
事实是他们变成僵尸以后
Other than the fact that they find brains delicious,
就只想着美味的脑花了
when it comes to zombies nobody knows nothin'.
轮到我了
My turn.
还是不是朋友了
Have we just met?
谢了
Thank you.
嗨 快点
Hey, hurry up.
我想在天黑前通过华盛顿
I want to get past DC before dark.
是啊 是啊
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
我说 他们什么都没有
I'm tellin' ya, there ain't nothin' there.
没有思维 没有记忆
No thoughts, no memories.
没有灵魂
No soul.
什么都没有
Nothin'.
他们也不算是死了
Well they're not dead.
他们没放弃追求
They want something.
是啊 追求脑髓
Yeah. Brains.
如果你没有灵魂
You can't want something if you're not conscious,
当你神志不清时 你就不会有追求了
if you don't have a soul.
我爸爸受伤的时候
When my pa was wounded,
他告诉我在他转变前把他捆起来
he told me to tie him up before he turned.
让我发誓在他死后帮他一把
Made me promise to show him mercy when he died.
打他的头部 你知道吗
Kill the brain, you know?
我做不到
I couldn't do it.
我下不了手
I couldn't hurt my pa,
不管他变成了什么
no matter what he'd become.
我凝视他的眼睛 我看了那么久
I stared into his eyes for the longest time, just
希望能从他的眼里看出一丝他自己的样子
looking for some sign he was still in there.
那你看到了吗
Did you see anything?
你后来怎么办的
What did you do?
我杀了它
I killed it.
可恶 小子
Damn, kid.
你居然放倒了你自己的老爸
You had to put down your own dad?
我没有杀他
Didn't kill him.
是它 宝盖头的它
Killed it.
但如果没有生命 你要怎么杀死它
But if it's not alive, how did you kill it?
一刀刺穿
Piked it.
就是这里 那是我杀的第一个僵尸
Right here. My first kill.
我总是祈祷他明白
I always wish he knew, you know,
我也算实现了我的承诺
somehow knew that I kept my promise.
有人 六点钟方向
Humans! Six o'clock!
看到了
I see them.
又是你的食人族朋友么
Is that more of your cannibal friends?
不 是别人
No. Something else.
前面
Up ahead!
他去哪
Where's he going?
嗨 小子
Hey! Kid!
怎么办
What do you think?
压过去吗
Plow right through?
不 我不想再把卡车弄坏了
No, I don't want to wreck the truck again.
下去解决掉他们 再赶路
Let's pike them and be on our way.
什么 我们在开慈善晚宴吗
Oh what, are we having a little mercy party?
嗨 低调一点
Hey, let's do this quietly.
附近可能还会有更多丧尸
There might be more of them nearby.
等等 等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
有点不对劲
Something's wrong.
恩 她说的对 看他们的脚
Yeah, she's right. Look at their feet.
呆在那别动
Hold it right there!
好吧 要么扔掉你的武器
All right, now drop your weapons
要么死
or die
一点都不含糊
right where you stand.
放下武器
Put down the weapons
要么就等着变僵尸吧
or eat brains.
天啊 好小子 我喜欢
God, I love that kid.
现在 我们只想要那个车
Now, we just want the vehicle.
好不
All right?
把卡车给我们
So give us the truck
就饶你们不死
and we'll let you live to die another day.
给他们卡车
Give them the truck!
什么也别给他们
Don't give them a goddamn thing!
加内特 好好算算
Do the math Garnett.
我们还有更重要的事
We have other priorities.
就给他们那个破卡车吧
Get them the damn truck.
听你朋友的吧
Listen to your friend there.
没有人想死
Nobody wants to die.
但卡车我们要定了
But we're taking that truck.
你做决定吧 加内特
Say the word, Garnett.
要仁慈
Have mercy
哦 要仁慈
Oh, have mercy
不管了
Let them have it.
卡车
The truck.
不管卡车了
Let them have the truck.
明智之举
Smart move.
好了伙计们 我们走
All right guys, let's go!
把那个破车扔了
And leave the junker!
他们走不了多远了
They're not gonna get very far.
墨菲
Murphy.
美得很
Beautiful.
北极光营地
雷蒙德 瓦尔迪兹警长
Sergeant Raymond Valdez.
三角洲部队 死亡
Delta Force. Deceased.
马克 哈蒙德中尉
Lieutenant Mark Hammond.
三角洲部队死亡
Delta Force. Deceased.
死亡原因
Cause of death.
不明
Unknown.
阿尔文 伯纳德 墨菲
Alvin Bernard Murphy.
也就是零号病人
AKA Patient Zero.
之前因为邮政欺诈
Previously serving three years in federal prison
在联邦监狱关了三年
for postal fraud.
强行社区服务 为咬痕组织工作
Compulsory volunteer, project Bite Mark.
状态
Status.
在去加利福尼亚州威尔逊山疾病控制中心实验室的路上
Believed to be en route to Mt. Wilson CDC lab, California.
加内特中士 国民警卫队队员
Sergeant Charles Garnett, National Guard.
携带着零号病人
Believed to be in possession of Patient Zero.
当前位置 费城南部某处
Current location, somewhere south of Philadelphia,
还有数量不明的平民一起
accompanied by an unknown number of civilians.
呼叫z市民
Come in, Citizen Z.
求救 求救
Mayday. Mayday.
这是三角洲X光小队的艾迪生 卡弗
This is Addison Carver with Delta-Xray-Delta.
呼叫市民z
Trying to contact Citizen Z.
呼叫市民z 我是艾迪卡弗
Come in, Citizen Z. Addy Carver.
-有求救信号 -听起来不是军方的
- Mayday. - Doesn't sound military.
略带东海岸口音
Slightly east coast accent.
我猜的话
I wonder.
九级以上可进入安全机密
Level nine top secret clearance only.
就是我啦
That would be me.
脸谱 朋友网 推特 火种
Facebook, Friendster, Twitter, Tinder.
真让人想起往事啊
A regular trip down memory lane.
指不定哪天我们就剩下这些东西了
Someday this will be all that's left of us.
艾迪生卡弗 又名艾迪
Addison Carver, AKA Addy.
26岁 学生
Age twenty-six. Student.
证实和零号病人前往威尔逊山
Believed to be accompanying Patient Zero to Mount Wilson
的咬痕组织的路上
regarding operation Bite Mark.
距离上次联系是七天以前
Last contact seven days ago.
状态
Status,
单身
single.
啊不对 状态是未知
I mean, status unknown.
真漂亮啊
What a tomato.
怎么了
What?
无意冒犯啊宝贝 你真该洗个澡了
No offense babe, but you need a bath.
是吗
Do I?
是啊
Yeah.
哦 好啊 那你上次换内裤
Oh, okay. Yeah, when was the last time
是什么时候 混小子
you changed your underwear goat-boy?
什么内裤
What underwear?
真恶心
Ewww!
嘿
Hey!
你们看得到了吗
Y'all see that?
就是他们
That's them, all right.
混蛋
Bastards.
看上去这次他们是想抢劫平民家庭了
Looks like they're trying to rob some poor family this time.
我要是插手的话他们就别想了 来吧
Not if I have anything to say about it. Come on.
我能不能说 别这么干
Would it matter at all if I said don't do this?
把武器放到地上
Drop your weapons on the ground
不然我就打爆你的头
or the first shot takes your head off.
你也听到了 快放下武器
You heard the man. Drop your weapons.
快
Now.
这是什么情况
What's this?
抢劫
A robbery.
放下武器
Drop your weapons.
赶紧的
Now.
别逼我把你们也杀了
I don't want to have to kill you.
再也不能冒险了
Never get out of the boat.
嘿 这玩意儿能再慢一点吗
Yo, can't this thing go any faster?
还没到加利福尼亚我就老死了
I'm gonna die of old age before we get to California.
你完全可以下去推车啊
You can always get out and push.
才不要 妹子 我可是特殊人物
No, not me, sister. I'm special.
每次和你说话都让我
Talking to you makes me wonder
对这次拯救人类之行感到更加迷茫
about this whole saving humanity thing.
停车
Stop the car!
是那一家子
Oh, it's the family.
我们不能再在这条路上走了
We got to get off this road.
完全没有任何新鲜事
Absolutley nothing new is going on
还会发生在这个日趋败落的世界
in this decimated world of ours.
看哪儿都是一样的绝望
It's the same desperation, the same devastation
一样的灾难
everywhere you look.
谁特么一天没事老放这个猫的视频
And who the hell keeps posting all these cat videos?
要早知道弹钢琴的猫
We should have known piano playing kittens
就是世界末日的预兆就好了
was a harbinger of the Apocalypse.
好
Okay.
别叫
Quiet!
我是查理加内特中士 呼叫北极光营地
This is Sergeant Charles Garnett calling Northern Light.
查理加内特中士 呼叫北极光营地 请回答 北极光营地
Charles Garnett calling Northern Light. Come in, Northern Light.
能看到我吗 z市民 你在吗 完毕
Can you read me? Citizen Z, are you there? Over.
在 这里是北极光营地
Yes, this is Northern Light for Garnett.
z市民回复中 加内特请说
Citizen Z hitting you back. Go for Garnett.
太好了 我们在这东西上花了几个小时了
Thank God. We've been trying to make this work for hours.
你们用什么在通话啊
What are you broadcasting on?
额 薯条人克劳尼
Uh, Clowny the french fry guy.
我们的队员卡弗 在得来速汽车餐厅找到的摄像头
One of our team, Carver jerry-rigged a drive-thru camera
艾迪 卡弗吗
Addy Carver?
是的
Yeah.
她在吗 我想打个招呼
Is she there? I wanna say hi.
哦 好啊
Oh, okay.
嗨 安迪
Hi, Addy.
嘿
Hey.
你那边怎么样啊
How's it going down there?
额 一团糟
Ummm, it's pretty eff'd up actually.
你那边怎么样啊
How's it going wherever you are?
你懂的 还不是老样子
Aww you know, same ol' same ol'.
忙着照看整个世界啊
Busy keeping an eye on the world.
我能帮上什么忙吗
What can I do for you folks?
我能点个十人份的巧克力奶昔和薯条吗
Can we get a chocolate shake and fries for ten thousand men?
能不能趁僵尸还没找到咱们 麻利点
Could we please get on with this before the Zs find us?
等等 那是墨菲吗
Wait. Is that Murphy?
太好了
Outstanding.
很高兴你还活着 先生
Glad to see you're still alive, sir.
但我们要是再不离开这条高速路就活不了了
Yeah but he won't be for long if we don't get off this highway.
我们急需其他的交通方式
We're in desperate need of alternate transpo.
我们要飞机 直升机或者热气球
We're looking for an airplane or a chopper or a hot air balloon.
能飞的就行
Anything airborne.
这倒是有一个
There is one thing.
我最近都有检测到
I've been monitoring some random transmissions
从感染控制应急总部
from what's left of the
传来的信号
Emergency Headquarters for Infection Control.
我能听到 但他们老是不回答我
I can hear them, but they don't respond when I reply.
挺混乱的
And it's pretty garbled.
迈侃多斯上将可能还被困在那儿
General McCandles might still be holed up there.
算你们走运
You're in luck.
我能看到那里有一辆直升机
I have a visual confirmation on that chopper.
看起来还在那儿
It looks like it's still there.
在哪儿
Where is it?
弗吉尼亚的麦克林 在华盛顿特区的西边
McLean, Virginia. Twenty clicks due west of Washington DC.
找找一栋被严重破坏的高楼
Look for a high-rise with structural damage
楼顶上停着一辆直升机
and a chopper on the roof.
那得向南走几百里呢
Now that's a hundred miles south from here.
我们要去西边 不是南边
We're going west, not south.
西边 你到底还想不想离开这高速路了
West. Do you want to get off the road or not?
他们来了
- Puppies and kittens! -
我们得撤了
We gotta go.
再见 艾迪森
Bye, Addison.
到了记得联系我
Call me when you get there.
感染控制应急总部 麦克林 弗吉尼亚
比我想象中差一点
Not exactly what I was hoping for.
这年头你要学会万事不要抱太大希望
One of these days you're gonna learn to quit hoping for things.
当我们把你丢在马路边的时候
You better hope not
你才最好不要抱什么希望
cuz that's when we leave your ass at the side of the road.
停 报上名来
Halt! Who goes there!
我是查理 加内特中士 国民警卫队的
Sergeant Charles Garnett, National Guard.
这是罗伯塔沃伦中尉
This is Lieutenant Roberta Warren,
- 来干什么的 - 他也是国民警卫队的
- State your business. - also National Guard.
我们正在执行一个高级任务
We're on a high priority mission
要将这个人带到加利福尼亚的疾病控制中心实验室
to get this man to a CDC lab in California.
我们是国家安全局的人派来
We were sent here by an Intell Officer from the NSA
找麦坎多斯上校的
to see General McCandles.
我们需要他帮我们找交通工具
We need his help finding transpo.
我们听说他有一辆直升机
We were told he has a helicopter.
是 他是有
Yeah, he's got a chopper.
但麦坎多斯上校是个大忙人
But General McCandles is a very busy man.
他还有一整个东海岸要管
He's got the entire east coast under his command.
没空搭理一堆要去送死的
He can't worry about some raggedy ass group of civilians
衣衫褴褛的平民组织
on a suicide mission.
我建议你们最好趁僵尸还没发现你们之前逃命吧
I suggest you move on before the infected find you.
长官 我们可不是什么衣衫褴褛的平民组织
Nothing raggedy ass about this group of civilians, sir.
这个男人身上带着
And this man has important information
抵抗僵尸病毒的重要信息
about a vaccine for the zombie virus.
他闻着一股僵尸味儿
He smells like a damn Z.
说得跟你很好闻一样
You don't smell so good yourself, septic tank.
你到底帮不帮我们
You gonna help us or not?
你们想见上校
You want to see the General?
那你们得贡献点什么
You're going to have to pay a tribute.
以表诚意
Gesture of goodwill to show him you're serious.
你想要什么
What kind of tribute you have in mind?
我们的药品已经断了一年了
Our medic has been MIA over a year.
我们需要止痛药 抗生素
We need painkillers. Antibiotics.
什么都行
Anything you got.
我去拿包
I'll get my bag.
我有阿司匹林 四环素 环丙沙星
I got aspirin, tetracycline, cipro.
足够抵挡多重感染了
That should knock out most any infection.
还有奥斯康定
And oxycontin.
奥斯康定 我们需要止痛药
The oxy. We need painkillers.
你还要不要见上校了
You want to see the General or not?
我们就这么点儿了
This is the last of our supply.
够了
That'll do.
嘿
Hey!
我这就带你们去见上校
The General will see you now.
你为什么要浪费我的时间
Why are you wasting my time?
麦坎多斯上校
General McCandles, sir.
这里有个国民警卫小队和几个平民
We have a National Guard unit and several civilians
想和你谈一谈
requesting permission to speak to you.
他们带来上帝了吗
Is sweet Jesus with them?
没有
No, sir.
- 那叫他们去死-  - 不太可能
- Then tell them to go to hell! - I don't believe so.
我还要打仗呢 我呼叫的空援呢
I've got a war to fight! Where's that close air support I ordered
告诉海军上将我要那些潜艇全部就位
Tell the Admiral I need those subs in position by 0800.
兄弟们 不惜一切守住阵地
Bravo Company, hold your position at all costs.
不惜一切
Repeat, all costs.
你们也听到了
You heard the General.
麦坎多斯上校
General McCandles, sir.
我们直接受命于总统
We're on a mission of extreme importance
执行这项高级任务
by direct order from the president.
这事儿十万火急 我们必须飞去威尔逊山的疾病控制中心实验室
It's imperative that we find air transport to Mt. Wilson CDC lab
- 不好意思我很忙- 那可是在加州
- Sorry, I'm busy. - in California.
我的援军呢
Where are my reinforcements?
你也听到了 快走吧
You heard the man. Time to go.
就这样
That's it?
你把我的奥斯康定都吐出来
I've a good mind to make you barf up my oxycontin.
医师 别冲动
Doc! Doc! Stand down!
你刚才是说 医师吗 就是医生那个医师吗
Did you say Doc? As in doctor?
是的 我们小队里有个医生
Yeah, our team includes a medical doctor.
为什么不早说 把他叫上来
Why didn't you say so? Send him up.
我这儿有个病员需要治疗
I have a wounded man in need of medical attention.
只能医生上去 你们在下面等着
Just the doctor. The rest of you wait here.
我行的
I got this.
好吧
All right.
嘿 嘿 嘿 跟他说直升飞机的事
Hey, hey, hey. Talk to him about the chopper.
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch.
我可是打算把那些奥克康定留着以后到加州聚会时嗨的
I was saving that oxy for a party when we got to Cali.
你就是那个医生吗
You the medic?
正是在下
I am indeed.
你是上校吗
You the General?
亚瑟 C 麦坎多斯 指挥中心的指挥官
General Arthur C. McCandles. Commander, Central Command,
感染反应部队
Infection Response Forces.
受伤的人呢
Where's your wounded man?
这儿
Right here.
不是被咬了
It's not a bite.
看起来很糟糕
This looks bad.
真的很糟糕
Real bad.
只是小抓伤
It's just a scratch.
不 这 这更像是坏死了
No, that's... that's more like gangrene.
能保住这条腿吗
Can you save the leg?
恐怕不行了 上校
I'm afraid not, General.
已经开始蔓延了
It's already starting to spread.
很快僵尸病毒就会袭遍全身
Soon the Z virus will take over.
现在我能做的
All I can do at this point is show you mercy
只有在时辰到了的时候为你祈祷了
when the time comes.
你就是这样看病的吗
You call that a diagnosis?
我只是说了实话
I call it the truth.
你要死了
You're gonna die.
命不久矣
And soon.
上一个也是这么说的
That's what the last guy said.
哦 哦
Oh! Oh!
瞧瞧这是谁
look who
你怎么看 狗狗
What do you think, pup?
我们能找另一个朋友吗
Could we use another friend?
和我不谋而合
My thoughts exactly.
真快啊
That was quick.
北极的事进展如何
How are things at the North Pole?
太棒了 今天有漂亮的极光 你一天过的如何
Awesome. Beautiful Aurora today. How's your day going?
有点孤单 很高兴有人谈话
Kinda lonely. Nice to have somebody to talk to.
我理解这种感受 在这我也有些孤独
I know the feeling. Gets lonely here too.
虽然一天忙着监视整个地球
Keeping an eye on the planet keeps you busy though.
知道你照看着我们 我感觉安全多了 你人真好
I feel safer just knowing you're there. You seem so cool.
我真想亲自和你见面
I wish I could meet you in person.
太忙了 但要见你肯定有时间
Super busy, but I'm sure that could be arranged.
你现在在干什么
What are you doing right now?
哇 你知道的
Aww you know.
老样子啦
Same ol', same ol'.
一千九十
One thousand ninety.
一千九十一
One thousand ninety-one.
一千九十二
One thousand and ninety-two.
好的 多克那进展怎么样
Okay, what's going on with Doc?
伙计们 我们得快点离开 事情会变糟的
Guys, if we don't get out of here soon this could get ugly.
哦 你是指更糟吧
Oh, you mean uglier.
听到了吗
Do you hear that?
听到什么
Hear what?
我什么也没听到
I don't hear anything.
嘘
Shhh.
像是多克
Sounds like Doc.
别啊
Make it stop!
没错是多克的叫声 但他在哪儿
That's Doc all right. But where the hell is he?
上面
Somewhere up there.
我们得上去找他
We're going up after him.
不 没门
No, you don't.
快让我们上去
Let us up now.
没有将军的命令没人可以上楼
Nobody goes upstairs without the General's orders.
我们现在就要上去
We go up now
否则我一枪崩掉你
or I scramble your egg-brain inside the shell.
你会后悔的
You'll be sorry.
你也会的 因为你和要我们一起
So will you cuz you're coming up with us.
一万 掩护我们
10K! Cover our flank.
不要让其他人或僵尸上去
Don't let man or zombie follow us up.
好的
Yes, sir.
一千九十三
One thousand ninety-three.
不
No.
一千九十四
Ninety-four.
上校在哪一层
What floor is the General on?
顶层
Top floor.
他可是上校 你觉得他在哪一层
He's the General, man. What floor do you think he's on?
这都是幻觉
My world is but an illusion.
我的世界只是一个幻觉
哦上帝 为什么我没有对那个佛教小妞
Oh God, why didn't I pay better attention
更疼爱一些
to that sweet little Buddhist chick I dated?
保持冷静
Stay calm.
我确定他们 我确定他们现在在找你
I'm sure they're... I'm sure they're watching you right now.
他们在找你
They're looking for you.
他们肯定在找你
They're looking for you right now.
他们不会把你一个人留在这儿
There's no way they'd just leave you here
和一个丑逼僵尸卡在通风井里
trapped in the air shaft with an ugly-ass zombie
他还想啃了我的脸
waiting to eat my face off!
哦 等等
Oh, wait.
哦
Oh.
哦 这才像话嘛
Oh, that's more like it.
我一直留着等到特殊场合再用
I was saving this for a special occasion.
就现在了
Like now.
快啊 吸一吸 快啊 快啊
Come on, suck it up. Come on. Come on.
简直爽歪歪
That's good shit, man.
冷静
Chill!
救命
Help!
又怎么了
Now what?
要做好任何事都可能发生的准备
Be ready for anything.
我又没有提过
Did I mention that
除了僵尸我还怕电梯
the one thing I have a phobia of aside from zombies is elevators.
你们不该惹毛上校的
Shouldn't have messed with the General.
是不是越变越热了
Is it getting hot in here?
嗨 过来 快开门
Hey, come on. Open the damn door.
我要从这出去
I got to get out of here.
放松 墨菲
Relax, Murphy.
不 不 我要出去 这缺氧
No, no, I got to get out. There's not enough oxygen.
冷静下来
Chill out!
迈克
Mack!
我在这 宝贝
I'm here, babe.
嗨 为什么电梯不动了
Hey, why aren't we moving?
一秒后会动的
It'll start in a second.
谢谢你 孩子 很好
Thank you, son. It's good.
我能为你做些什么吗
Can I do anything for you?
保证这些结打紧了
Make sure those knots are tight.
我快变身了
It's not gonna be long now.
我打的双半钩 像你教我的一样
It's double-half-hitch. Just like you taught me.
只是确认一下
Just be sure.
答应我
Promise me
时辰到了
you'll do what we talked about
你会想我们约定好的那样做的
when the time comes.
答应我
Promise me.
我答应
I promise.
像我们商量的那样
Just like we talked about.
我发誓
I swear.
别发誓
Don't swear.
你母亲从不喜欢这样
Your mother never liked that.
我保证
I promise.
好的
Good.
我知道你一定会做出正确的选择
I could always trust you to do the right thing.
你是个好孩子
You're a good boy.
你的母亲
Your mother,
她一定会为长大后的你感到骄傲的
she'd be proud of the man you're growing up to be.
让我再吸一口
Give me another puff.
好吗
Will ya?
你可别介意
Ya know, now don't take offense.
你的口气比你的脸
But the only thing worse than that mug of yours
还臭
is your breath.
别咬我的手指 混蛋
Not my fingers, you animal!
我只是让你吸一口而已
I was offering you the last hit.
算了 还是我自己享用吧
Well, fine. I'll bogart it myself then.
跟你说过了 这东西用途可多了
A thousand and one uses, I tell ya.
不是吧
Well I'll be damned.
你好像挺享受的
I think you're stoned.
我看根本就不需要什么疫苗
Hell, we don't need a vaccine.
来几十亿吨上好大麻
Just need a few billion tons of some primo Ganja,
这个世界就太平了
and the world would be just fine.
摩根 亨雷医生
Doctor Morgan Henley.
对那些被你浸泡在大麻酚里的脑细胞而言
Does that name ring a bell
这个名字应该很熟悉吧
in any of those cannabinol soaked brain cells you have left
我好像有点吸多了
I must be really stoned.
产科医生吗
Obstetrics, huh?
我好好奇那到底是什么样子
I wonder what that must have been like.
把所有美好的小天使们带到人间
Bringing all them beautiful little angels into the world.
能够见证这么多奇迹的发生
I mean just to be present for so many miracles.
可惜这些小家伙以后都会变成僵尸
Yeah, it's a bummer all those babies grew up to be zombies.
你知道吗
You know,
我曾经也有过小孩
I got a kid out there somewhere.
我从未告诉过其他人
I never told anybody that before.
那是我才19岁
I had him when I was 19.
还太年轻
Too young.
没有肩负对他的责任
Wasn't really around for him like I should've been.
也从未去好好了解他
Never really got to know him.
我一直告诉自己
Kept telling myself maybe you know
也许某天 我可以跟他打个电话
someday I... I would just call him up.
把那些遗失的时光给补回来
Make up for lost time.
遗失的时光
Lost time. Lost time.
我都不知道他现在是死是活
And I don't even know if he's alive or dead.
救命
Help!
来人啊
Somebody!
有没有人
Anybody!
救命
Help!
大家必须守住阵线
Bravo Company must hold their positions
直到援军赶到 如果防线崩溃了
until the reinforcements arrive. If their line is broken,
就无法阻止感染从这里
there's nothing to stop the infected
传到大洋那边去了
between here and the ocean.
你告诉空军中校
You tell that wing commander
如果他不能让那先飞机马上起飞
if he doesn't get those planes in the air right now
我就亲自过去
I'm gonna come down there personally
把他的头拧下来
and tear his head off his shoulders
用他的脑袋把僵尸打个半死
and beat the damn zombie horde to death with his bloody skull.
快看呐
Well, well, well.
我们好像有客人了
What do we have here?
不听话的野狗总是听不懂人话
Insubordinate curs can't take no for an answer?
我们走着瞧吧
We'll see about that, eh?
- 怎么不动了 - 发生什么了
- Why aren't we moving? - What's going on?
好了 大家都冷静点
All right, everyone needs to relax.
别跟我们耍花样
Don't mess with us.
我没有跟你们耍花样
I'm not messing with you, man.
要是发生任何事 你会是第一个遭殃的
Anything happens, you'll be the first to go.
我要离开这里
I got to get out of here!
墨菲 不要
Murphy! No!
别开枪
Don't fire!
那个笨蛋太欠抽了
I should have slapped that fool harder.
墨菲
Murphy!
墨菲 墨菲
Murphy! Murphy!
好吧 沃伦 你跟我走
All right Warren, you come with me.
你们几个呆在这 防止他倒回来
You guys stay here in case he comes back.
知道了
Got it.
还好吗
You okay?
恩
Uh huh.
我们赶紧离开这
Let's get out of here.
兄弟
Dude,
我还真有点不厌烦了
you're really starting to marsh my mellow.
一个小时以前你就该派上用场了
Well I coulda used you about an hour ago.
听着
Look, man.
和你在一起挺有趣 不过
It's been fun, but
现在你得回老家了
I think it's time you go home now.
你有点把我吓到了 老兄
You're starting to creep me out, man.
让我来给你个了断吧
Let's just get this over with.
摩根 亨雷医生
Doctor Morgan Henley.
愿你安息
I give you mercy.
好了
Okay.
没事了
There.
现在我该怎么出去
Now how am I gonna get out of here?
沃伦
Warren!
救救我 有人吗
Help! Somebody!
多克 多克
Doc? Doc?
有人吗
Anybody!
多克 是你吗
Doc, is that you?
墨菲
Murphy?
墨菲 是你吗
Murphy, is that you?
坚持住 多克
Hang in there, Doc.
会有人来帮你的
Someone will come help you.
不过不是我
Just not me.
我没弹药了
I'm out of ammo.
我也是
Me too.
快看这是谁啊
Well look who.
可能是他们中最后一个人了
I think that's the last of them.
大家都没事吧
Is everybody okay?
恩
Ehhh.
有人看到墨菲了吗
Anybody seen Murphy?
墨菲 墨菲
Murphy! Murphy!
不用喊了 我在这
You don't have to shout. I'm right here.
你不要再往僵尸堆里跑了 行吗
You don't sneak up on people in the zombie apocalypse, okay?
抱歉 抱歉
Sorry, sorry.
我知道多克在哪了
I know where Doc is.
哪
Where?
见鬼
Holy shit.
我们弹药了
I'm out of ammo.
我也是
Me too.
我还有这个
I got this.
加内特
Garnett!
找掩护
Take cover!
不
No!
大家没事吧
Is everybody okay?
没事
Yeah.
墨菲 多克在哪
Murphy, where's Doc?
他就在通风井下面
He was down that air shaft.
什么
What?
赶紧找架直升机然后离开这
Let's go find that helicopter and get out of here.
马上
Now.
没有别的意思 总统太太
No disrespect Madame President,
但你实在是不适合在战争中
but you're not fit to lead a gang of kindergartners
带领一群幼儿园教师
in a dirt clod war.
更别说这个国家正处于非常危险时期
Let alone this great nation in a moment of grave national peril
就像现在所处的情境一样
like we find ourselves in now.
嘿 等等
Hey, hey, hey!
等候多时了
I've been waiting for you.
靠
Ah, crap.
什么都用不了了
Nothing works anymore.
根本用不了
Nothing.
你们几个到底想要干什么
What do you people want anyway?
我们正在执行一个事关人类生死任务
We're on a mission that just might save the human race.
这个人血液里有种抗体
This man has antibodies in his blood
可以做成僵尸疫苗
needed to make a zombie vaccine.
我们被要求把他送到加州疾病防治中心的实验室
We've been tasked with getting him to a CDC lab in California.
必须要活的
Alive.
我们需要你的直升机
We need your helicopter.
你们干嘛不早说
Well hell, why didn't you say so sooner?
我会亲自把你们送去
I'll fly you there myself.
她很漂亮 不是吗
She's beautiful, isn't she?
这是个啥 逗我们吗
What is this, some kind of joke?
她的确需要点保养 不过
Sure, she needs a little maintenance. But,
细心看护
with some TLC,
再找一些备用的零件
a little help scrounging a few spare parts,
马上就可以让你们到加州了
I'll have you to California in no time.
混蛋
Jackass!
嘿
Hey.
我一个朋友为了这堆破铜烂铁送命了
A friend of mine died trying to get to that pile of junk.
你和多克是朋友吗
You and Doc were friends?
一起打过牌 虽然只有一次
We played cards... once.
这就是战争 孩子
This is war, son.
我们失去了很多朋友
We've all lost friends.
所有我认识的人都死了
Hell, everybody I ever knew is dead.
一点也不稀奇
Why am I not surprised?
我不怎么喜欢你
You know I don't like you.
不喜欢我的人多了去了
Well get in line.
麦坎多斯上将
General McCandles.
长官
Sir.
感谢你的好意 不过我们得找别的交通工具了
Thank you, but I think we'll find alternate transportation.
你觉得我疯了 是吗
You think I'm insane, don't you?
也许我真疯了
Well maybe I am.
太多人死去
Too much death.
太多好人英年早逝
Too many good men sent to an early grave.
太多僵尸
Too many zombies.
退下 让我来
Stand down! I got this!
来吧 你们这群吃人的败类
Come here you Godless brain eating scum!
我要把你们拉入地狱
I'll see you in Hell!
多克呢
What happened to Doc?
他没能逃过这一劫
He didn't make it.
僵尸来了
Zombies.
噢
Oh, whoa, whoa.
天呐 那不是
Oh God, is that...
是多克
It's Doc.
我们必须
Someone's gotta...
我来吧
I'll do it.
史蒂芬 多克 贝克
Steven "Doc" Beck.
愿你安息
I give you mercy.
你他妈干嘛 沃伦
What the hell, Warren?
你想杀死我吗
You trying to kill me?
你还活着
You're alive?
我当然还活着
Damn straight I'm alive.
我们都以为你死了
We thought you were dead.
我也以为我死了
Well so did I.
有个傻子朝我被卡住的通风井扔了个手榴弹
Some numbskull threw a grenade in the air shaft I was stuck in.
快过来
Well hurry up!
给你
Here.
来吧
Come on.
啵一个吧 宝贝
Give me a kiss, baby.
我得走了
Well I should let you go.
我知道你一直忙着注意
I'm sure you're busy with
世界各地的情况
keeping an eye on the world and all.
没错
Yeah.
我的狗狗饿了 我必须给它喂食
I got a hungry dog here I better go feed.
和你聊天很高兴
Nice talking to you.
希望我们以后能见面
I hope we get to meet someday.
我也是
I'd really like that.
晚安
Good night.
甜心王子
Sweet prince.
晚安 窈窕淑女
Good night, fair lady.
接下来给所有寂寞的人送上一首歌
Here's a song for all the lonely people out there,
送给还存活着的任何人
which is just about everybody that's left.
如果有人和你一起度过了世界末日
So if you've got somebody to go through the Apocalypse with,
你一定要好好珍惜
you better watch their backs.
因为没有多人存活了
Cuz there ain't many of us left.
哦 对了
And oh yeah,
我想把这首歌送给艾迪生 卡弗
I'd like to dedicate this song to Addison Carver,
不论你在哪
wherever you are.
我想把这首歌送给艾迪生 卡弗
I'd like to dedicate this song to Addison Carver,
不论你在哪
wherever you are.
我只跟他说过两次话 拜托
I talked to the guy twice. Come on.
你知道吗 孩子
You know kid,
我一直在想你跟我说的关于你爸的事
I've been thinking about what you told me about your dad
你多么希望他知道你做了对的事
and how you wished he knew you did the right thing
帮他个忙 就像你答应的那样
giving him mercy like you promised.
然后呢
Yeah?
我只是想让你知道
Well I just want you to know
你爸知道你所做的一切
your dad knows what you did for him.
他知道你做了正确的事 知道你遵守了诺言
And he knows you did the right thing. You kept your promise.
谢谢
Thanks.
我很抱歉 爸爸
I'm sorry, papa.
我爱你
I love you.